The Unbreakable Mask and
the Shattered Bubble
（オオノキ）ナルト…　こっちのマダラは
わしらに任せい。
Naruto…
Let us deal with this Madara!
必ずケリをつける！
I swear we shall settle this
once and for all!
それが　これまでの憎しみの
呪いを止める第一歩となる。
It will be our first step in stopping
the curse of hatred
we've been under until now!
マダラと同じように　かつて憎しみを
生み出してきた　わしらには→
Like Madara,
we are similarly guilty
of stirring up hatred in the past.
そうしなければならない
責任がある！
It is our responsibility to
make things right!
ここは安心して　わしらに任せろ。
Rest assured and leave this to us!
じゃから
あっちのマダラは　お前に任せる。
So… You go take care
of the other Madara!
それが　これからの希望を進める
第一歩となる！
That will become the first step
in promoting hope for the future.
Old one, new one…
（綱手）古いヤツ　新しいヤツ
どちらのマダラにも勝つことが→
Defeating both Madaras will bring
an end to this war!
この戦争の終わりを意味する。
私たちは　この戦場で
お前を守る。
We will protect you
on this battlefield!
だから　お前も向こうで戦い
私たちを守れ！
So protect us by fighting
over there!
Clone Naruto… I entrust you with
this message from the Five Kage.
分身ナルト　お前に火影から
この言葉を預ける！
（みんな）勝つぞ！
We will win!
（ナルト）うん…。
Yeah…
ぜってぇ勝つ！
We're going to win!
（ビー）おい…。
Hey…
落ち着け　ナルト。
バカ野郎　この野郎。
Chill out, Naruto…
Fool, ya fool.
クソッ　硬ぇ…　ヒビも入らねえ。
Damn, it's so hard.
I couldn't even put a crack in it.
（マダラ）すり抜けてもよかったが→
I could've let him pass
through me…
But he couldn't even
damage this mask.
しょせん　面に傷ひとつも
つけられないか…。
九尾をコントロールした　その力
こんなものではないだろう。
I hope that's not all the power
you can muster
to control the Nine Tails…
《老紫：溶遁　灼河流岩の術！》
Lava Style:
Scorching Rocks Jutsu!
アチッ！
Hot!
《やぐら：水遁　水鏡の術》
Water Style…
Aqua Mirror Jutsu!
《コイツら…》
These guys…
《同じ力で…》
…have the same power…!
これは…。
This is…
This jutsu… Is it Utakata?
《この術は　ウタカタ…》
((その子から離れろ！
Step away from that girl!
うっ！
A Shadow Clone?
《ウタカタ：影分身…》
What a bother…
ぐっ…。
あっ！
おとなしく捕まり…。
Give it up and
let yourself be caught!
No!
(（ホタル）ダメ！
その方は敵ではありません！))
He is not an enemy!
このチャクラ…
ウタカタ　お前　人柱力だったのか。
This chakra…
Utakata, you were…a Jinchuriki?
お前もな。
You too, huh?
行方不明になってしまったって
風の噂には聞いてたが→
I heard rumors that
you had gone missing.
やっぱり暁に…。
So the Akatsuki got you, after all.
ああ。　お前たちと別れたあと
ヤツらに待ち伏せされていた。
Yeah…
After I left you guys,
they were lying in wait for me.
((ここで　初めて師匠と
出会ったのですね。
This is where I first
met you, Master.
ホタル　少し　ここで
待っていてくれないか。
Hotaru… Will you wait here
for just a while?
どうかしました？
Is something the matter?
霧隠れの暗部に会う。
もう逃げるのはやめだ。
I'm going to meet with
the Mist's Anbu Black Ops.
I'm done running.
お前との修業の旅の許しを得る。
I'm going to get their permission
to travel and train you.
はい！
Yes, sir!
《やはり　応答はない。
ツルギたちに何かあったのか？》
No response, after all.
Did something happen to Tsurugi
and his men?
六尾の人柱力。
The Six Tails' Jinchuriki…
お前たちか。　ツルギをやったのは。
Are you the ones…
who killed Tsurugi and the others?
世界をつくりあげる。
I'm going to build a new world.
そのために　お前が必要だ。
And for that, I need you.
いや…　お前の中の尾獣がな。
Rather, I need the Tailed Beast
inside you.
そういうことか。
So that's it.
もらうぞ　六尾。
I'm taking you…Six Tails.
チッ。
うあ～っ！！
やっと本気を出したか。
Finally, you're taking this seriously.
それこそが　我々が求める力。
Now that's the power we seek…
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu…
行け。
Go!
捕らえたか。
It's been captured.
これくらいは
やってもらわないとな。
I expected as much out of you.
さぁ　来い。　六尾！
Now come, Six Tails!
ホタル…。
Hota…ru…
You…must live…
(お前は生きろ…))
((師匠…))
Master…
なんで…。
Why…
なんで　一人で
森になんか　行ったんだよ！？
Why did you go into
the forest alone?!
If you had escaped with Hotaru,
you'd still be…
ホタルと一緒に逃げてりゃ　今頃…。
The Shinobi Tracking Unit from
the village was in the forest.
森には　里の追い忍が…。
逃げることに疲れたんだ。
I grew tired of running.
里と和解し　大手を振って
生きていきたかった。
I wanted to reconcile with
the village and live in peace.
一生　逃げ回る生活から
抜け出したかった。
I wanted to stop living like a fugitive.
逃げ回る生活に
ホタルを巻き込みたくなかった。
And I wanted to spare Hotaru
a life constantly on the run.
ウタカタ　お前…。
Utakata, you…!
なんで　そんな気持になったのか。
I wonder why I started
feeling that way?
なんで　そんな夢を願ったか。
Why did I wish for such a dream?
今となっては無意味なことだった。
Well, it's all meaningless now.
俺は　信じていた自分の師匠に
裏切られたと思いこみ→
I convinced myself that the master
I trusted had betrayed me.
And so, I closed off my heart.
ずっと心を閉ざして　生きてきた。
人を信じることができなかった。
I didn't know how to trust people.
だが…　そんな俺を
なぜか　ホタルは信じてくれた。
And yet, Hotaru put her faith
in someone like me.
ホタルも人に言えない宿命を背負って
生きてきた。
Hotaru was also burdened with
a fate she hid from others.
The same way we Jinchuriki are.
俺たち　人柱力と同じように…。
もしかしたら
自分と同じ人間じゃないかって→
Maybe she sensed that
you and she were alike?
感じていたんじゃねえのか？
ホタル…。
Hotaru…
((ホタル。
誰も傷つけたくなかった。
Hotaru…
I didn't want to hurt anybody.
なのに　私は　ナルトさんを…。
And yet, I hurt Naruto
and Sir Utakata!
ウタカタ様を傷つけてしまった。
俺は　ここにいる。
ナルトも俺も無事だ。
I'm right here. Naruto and I
are both alive.
私は…。
ホタル。
I…
Hotaru?
私は　ウタカタ様を裏切った。
I… I betrayed you, Sir Utakata.
こんな私なんか　術もろとも
なくなってしまえばいい！
I should just disappear along
with this jutsu!
ダメだ。　そんなことは許さない。
No! I won't allow that to happen.
弟子は
師匠の言うことを聞くものだ。
A student should listen to her master.
今　師匠って…。
You said… "Master"…
帰るぞ　ホタル。
We're going home, Hotaru.
いったいどうした？
ダメ？
What's wrong?
No!
いけません。　ウタカタ様
この私のもとから離れて。
No… Sir Utakata…
Please get away from me!
Please run!
逃げてください。
ホタル！
Hotaru!
もう　私の力では
おさえることはできない。
I cannot suppress it any longer
with my own strength!
このまま私を引き裂いて
禁術が暴発してしまいます。
This Forbidden Jutsu is going
to tear me apart…
and explode.
大丈夫だ。
ウタカタ様。
It's all right.
Sir Utakata…
(師匠を信じろ))
Believe in your master.
ホタルは風に吹かれるまま→
I was like a bubble floating
aimlessly in the wind
あてどなく漂うシャボン玉のような
俺に道を示してくれた。
and Hotaru showed me the way.
俺は　ホタルの師匠として
生きていく決心をした。
I made up my mind to
become Hotaru's teacher.
だが　皮肉なものだな。
Isn't it ironic?
新たな道を踏み出そうとした
矢先に命を奪われ→
Just as I was about to
make good on my decision,
my life was snatched away
from me.
生き返ったと思ったら
自分の意思とは関係なく→
I was resurrected,
only to discover that
I have no will of my own,
別の道を歩かされている。
and am forced to walk
a different path.
アンタを操ってるのは
暁さえ利用して→
The ones manipulating you
used the Akatsuki too,
世界を自分の思いどおりに
しようと企んでるヤツらだ。
and are hell bent on
controlling the world.
そんなヤツらの
言いなりでいいのか？
Are you just going to do
what the likes of them order you to?
もし　ホタルと再会したら
何も言えず→
If you see Hotaru again,
you might be forced to fight her
without being able to say anything!
戦うことに
なるかもしれねえんだぞ。
アンタなら　自分の意思で
もとに戻れるはずだ。
You have the will to
take yourself back.
こんな無意味な戦いは…。
ナルト。
This is a meaningless fight.
Naruto…
こんな状況のせいか
つい本心を話してしまった。
I don't know if it's because of
these circumstances or not, but…
I just ended up telling you
my true feelings.
話につきあってくれて
ありがとう。
Thanks for listening…
ナルト！
Naruto!
《水遁　泡沫の術》
Water Style: Bubble Jutsu!
すまねえ　ビーのおっちゃん。
Sorry, Octopops!
《フウ：秘伝　鱗粉隠れの術》
Secret Tradition…
Scaled Sneak Jutsu.
このサングラス　遮光最高クラス。
My shades are the best…
So the light, with my eyes don't mess!
悪意は
ちゃんと見えてんだってばよ！
I can still see through their evil intent!
（八尾）今のは　ユギトじゃねえか。
Wasn't that Yugito just now?
コイツらは元人柱力どもだ。
These guys are former Jinchuriki.
しかも全員　片目は写輪眼で→
On top of that, each of them
もう片方が輪廻眼。
has a Sharingan in one eye
and a Rinnegan in the other.
命を奪われ駒にされた挙句→
Not only did they lose their lives,
両目をあんなキモイもんにされて→
their eyes were turned into
those disgusting things.
かわいそうなユギトだ。
Poor Yugito…
お前も
もしかしたら　あっち側で→
This could have easily
happened to you.
あんなになってたかもしんねえな。
笑えねえ。
This is no joke.
あんなひどい目に
あわせやがって激怒。
To see them like that
I feel rage and grief…
でも　あんな
キモイ目にされなくて安堵。
But me not getting eyes
like that is still a relief…
（八尾）テメエはどのみち
グラサンだけどな。
Well, you always wear
shades anyway.
ああなりたくなきゃ
気ぃ抜くなよ。
If you don't want to end up like that,
don't let your guard down!
マダラの目も同じだってばよ。
Madara's eyes are the same.
前してた面と違って
穴が２つある。
His mask's different from
the one he used to wear before.
It's got two openings!
この面は
前のと違って特別製でな。
Unlike the previous one,
this mask was specially made.
頑丈な戦闘用だ。
It's battle-grade tough.
いつも隠してた左目は→
So the left eye you always kept hidden
was a Rinnegan,
長門やあっちのマダラと同じ
輪廻眼だったってわけか。
just like Nagato and
that other Madara.
お前らマダラは　俺たちが止める。
We're going to stop both you Madaras!
お前ら…　だと？
《カブト：口寄せ　穢土転生》
((こ…　これは…。
僕が何の手札もなく
キミに会いに来るとでも？
そう　キミは断れない。
キサマ…　それをどこで手に入れた？
(安心していいよ。
これは誰にもしゃべってない))
カブトめ…。
お前らって
どういうことだ　この野郎。
マダラってアイツのことだろ？　バカ野郎。
フフフ…。
なんなら　かつての名
トビでもいいぞ。
戦争の始まった今
名前など　どうでもいい。
マダラ　トビ　好きに呼べ。
お前　いったい誰なんだってばよ？
俺は誰でもない。
誰でもいたくないのさ。
ただ　月の眼計画を
成せれば　それでいい。
絶望しかないこの世界に
存在する価値はない。
お前たち人柱力は
尾獣を取り付けさせられ→
絶望ばかりを見てきた。　違うか？
お前たちだったら　この絶望を
少しは理解できるだろう。
尾獣と一緒にいることが…。
不幸せだと
勝手に思いこむんじゃねえよ！
テメエにとっちゃあ
価値のねえ　この世界でも→
勝手に戦争まで起こしておいて
誰でもねえなんて→
そんなんでごまかして
通用すると思ってんのか！？
頭きた。
ぜってぇ　その面を
ひっぺがしてやる！
まずは　俺が行く。　ウィー！！
この面　はがすには…。
骨がおれるぞ。
イッ…。
八尾　九尾
俺はお前らを手に入れて→
月の眼を手に入れる！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手→
１１組の皆さんによる→
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。